Guide to the Angela Shelf Medearis Papers
The Wittliff Collections
Angela Shelf Medearis Papers
1983-2001
The Wittliff Collections
Medearis, Angela Shelf, 1956-
SWWC.057
25 Linear Feet
36 boxes Plus oversize.
Annotated drafts, typescripts, page proofs, galleys, correspondence,photographs, notes, and newsclippings dating from 1984-2001 represent the writing career of award-winning children's book writer, Angela Shelf Medearis.
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Angela Medearis, 2001.
Biographical Notes
Children's author and cookbook writer Angela Shelf Medearis was born on November 16, 1956, in Hampton, Virginia. In 1975, she married Michael Rene Medearis, and the couple moved to Austin, Texas. She attended Southwest Texas State University, has one daughter, Deanna, and one grandchild, Anysa. After working as a secretary for a number of years Ms. Medearis began writing full time in 1987. She founded Book Boosters in 1988, a non-profit, grant supported, multicultural reading program tutoring and teaching literacy to grade school children. Her sister Sandra currently directs the program. In 1990, Medearis published her first book, Picking Peas for a Penny, a picture book counting rhyme. According to Medearis, "Picture books are a child's first step into a lifetime of reading. That is why I feel that my job is important. I want to write in such an interesting and exciting way that the memory of reading my book, and the information I've related about a particular event, will linger with a young reader for a lifetime." Medearis has gone on to publish dozens of children's books about Black Americans with real life themes, as well as history books geared towards young readers, such as Come This Far to Freedom (1993), and brief biographies of Coretta Scott King and Ida B. Wells.
Medearis routinely visits schools and performs storytelling, she produced Children's Radio Bookmobile for the University of Texas at Austin (a weekly program featuring multicultural children's literature), and curated Black American exhibits for the George Washington Carver Museum in Austin. Additionally, Medearis (and her husband, Michael) act as a consultants and writers for Scott Foresman, Scholastic, and Macmillan publishers, creating or contributing textbooks and children's books. Among many other awards, Medearis won the first ever Teddy, a children's-book award presented by Laura Bush (Poppa's New Pants, 1996). In 1997, Texas Monthly magazine featured Ms. Medearis and described her as the best-selling children's book author in Texas, with over 1.5 million copies of works in print. "I write the kind of books I always longed to find in the library when I was a child. Every child needs to find a reflection of himself or herself when looking for a book in the library or bookstore."
Scope and Contents
Annotated drafts, typescripts, page proofs, galleys, correspondence, photographs, notes, and newsclippings dating from 1984-2001 represent the writing career of award-winning children's book writer, Angela Shelf Medearis. Over one half of the collection is comprised of materials related to the development and creation of Medearis' works (children's books, books for young readers, cookbooks, articles, poetry, and video projects). Other series include Correspondence, Subject Files, Newsclippings, Publicity, Awards, Calendars, Photographs, Personal Programs, and Artwork, the bulk of which also relate directly to Medearis' writing career.
Juvenile literature; African American women authors; Cookbooks; American poetry -- African American authors; Illustrated children's books; Medearis, Angela Shelf, 1956-
- Children's Books, 1987-2000, undated
  Series Description
  Annotated drafts, typescripts, page proofs, galleys, correspondence, and notes represent the creation and development of Medearis' children books. Materials have been arranged in chronological order, beginning with the earliest dates. Extensive annotated drafts and correspondence with editors and illustrators makes this series highly illustrative of Medearis' working process. Additional publisher and editor correspondence can be found in the Correspondence series, and Publicity correspondence in the Publicity series.
  - 1987
    - The Bird with the Stolen Feathers - typescript drafts (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1990
    - Aunt Oreta's Courtship / Aunt Oreta's Valentine (unpublished) - typescript (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Alexis the Alarm - typescript draft (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Ant Can't - typescript draft (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Building the Alphabet - typescript draft (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Picking Peas for a Penny: Drafts and correspondence, 1988-1990 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Picking Peas for a Penny: Color proofs (oversize), 1988-1990 (Box 36)
    - Picking Peas for a Penny: Galleys, 1988-1990 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Picking Peas for a Penny: Publicity and order forms, 1988-1990 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Picking Peas for a Penny: green felt pea pod and paper sack with pea seeds, 1988-1990 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - UnBearable - typescript draft (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - We Are a Family - typescript draft (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 1991
    - At the Library - typescript draft (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - A Blue Balloon Birthday - typescript draft (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Dancing with the Indians - Research and correspondence (clippings and photocopies), 1990-1992 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Dancing with the Indians - Drafts (text and drawings), 1990-1992 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Dancing with the Indians - Proofs, 1990-1992 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Goodnight Girls! - typescript draft (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Kyle's First Kwanzaa - typescripts, proofs (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Mary's Mail - typescript draft (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - My Name is Kaysha - notes, photographs, and drafts (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - On the Playground - typescript draft (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Willie and the Weed - typescript drafts (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - 1993
    - Gund Bear projects- Sam and Snuffles, and Snuffles (unpublished) (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Group folder: "Harry's House, The Copy Cat, The Queen Had an Idea, and other works in progress" including "Our Tree," "Daddy Me and the Tree," "Big Mama and Grandma Ghana," "Drums," "A Mouse Came to My Sister's Wedding," "I Am What I Am" with fax stating similarity to Medearis' childhood experiences (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Group folder: "Michael Can," "Mommy and Marcy," "Marcy Knows" (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - 1994
    - Annie's Gifts - typescripts, correspondence, and proofs, 1989-1994 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Barry and Bennie - drafts (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Cameron Thompson, Super Detective - drafts (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Christmas Riddle - Page layouts, 1991-1994 (Map-case Drawer 6)
    - Christmas Riddle - Correspondence, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Fiddler Man (unpublished) - Typescripts and correspondence, 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Fiddler Man (unpublished) - Mock-up (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Little Louis and the Jazz Band - Research, 1992-1994 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Little Louis and the Jazz Band - Drafts, 1992-1994 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Little Louis and the Jazz Band - Sketches, including letter from artist Anna, January 1992 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Little Louis and the Jazz Band - Page proofs and Galleys, 1992-1994 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Little Louis and the Jazz Band - Dust jacket, 1992-1994 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Little Louis and the Jazz Band - Correspondence, 1992-1994 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - No Snow - Draft, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Our People - Drafts, 1992-1994 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Our People - Draft page layout with illustrations (b/w), 1992-1994 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Our People - Illustrations (color) - also includes samples for Treemonisha, 1992-1994 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Our People - Cover art, 1992-1994 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Our People - Color page proofs, 1992-1994 (Map-case Drawer 6)
    - Our People - As published as Reading / Writing Performance Assessment, 1992-1994 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - 1995
    - Brother Crocodile and Sister Hen - Research (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Brother Crocodile and Sister Hen - Draft (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Freedom Riddle - Research, 1988-1995 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Freedom Riddle - Drafts, 1988-1995 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Freedom Riddle - Galleys / proofs, 1988-1995 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Pappa's New Pants - Research, 1993-1995 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Pappa's New Pants - Drafts, 1993-1995 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Pappa's New Pants - Galleys, 1993-1995 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Pappa's New Pants - Correspondence, 1993-1995 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Pappa's New Pants - Publicity, 1993-1995 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - The Singing Man - Research, 1992-1995 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - The Singing Man - Drafts, 1992-1995 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - The Singing Man - Mock-up (b/w), 1992-1995 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - The Singing Man - Foul matter returned from publisher- original annotated typescript, galley proofs (oversize), 1992-1995 (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Skin Deep - poster advertising author reading at Barnes & Noble, 1995 (Map-case Drawer 6)
    - Sugar and Junior - Drafts, 1992-1995 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Sugar and Junior - Illustrations (black and white) and draft layout, 1992-1995 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Too Much Talk - Research, 1991-1999 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Too Much Talk - First draft, annotated typescript, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Too Much Talk - Drafts, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Too Much Talk - Annotated mock-up (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Too Much Talk - Dust jacket flap text draft, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Too Much Talk - Cover art proofs (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Too Much Talk - Play adaptation, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - We Play on a Rainy Day - Drafts, 1993-1995 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - We Play on a Rainy Day - Page layouts (b/w) (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - We Visit Grandma - typescript draft (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - 1996
    - The 100th Day of School - Drafts, 1994-1996 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - The 100th Day of School - Page proofs, 1994-1996 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Boxcar Children Series- Mystery at the Alamo - Correspondence with Evelyn Coleman (author of this title, Medearis served as editor), 1996 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Boxcar Children Series- Mystery at the Alamo - Annotated typescript, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Boxcar Children Series- Mystery at the Alamo - Galleys, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Boxcar Children Series- Mystery on the Movie Set - Draft, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Haunts - short stories including "Scared Silly," "The Fiddler Man," "The Woman Who Wanted to Be a Witch," and others - Proposal, 1994-1996 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Haunts - short stories including "Scared Silly," "The Fiddler Man," "The Woman Who Wanted to Be a Witch," and others - Drafts, 1994-1996 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Haunts - short stories including "Scared Silly," "The Fiddler Man," "The Woman Who Wanted to Be a Witch," and others - Galleys, 1994-1996 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Here Comes the Snow - Galleys, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Spray Paint Mystery - Synopsis, 1996-1997 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Spray Paint Mystery - Illustrations (b/w), 1996-1997 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Spray Paint Mystery - Publicity/contest, 1996-1997 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Tailypo - Drafts, 1995-1997 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Tailypo - Galleys, 1995-1997 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - We Eat Dinner in the Bathtub - Drafts, 1988-1996 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - We Eat Dinner in the Bathtub - Illustrations (b/w), 1988-1996 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - We Eat Dinner in the Bathtub - Galley and dummy, 1988-1996 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - 1997
    - Champions! – proposal (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - The Ghost of Sifty-Sifty Sam - Research, 1991-1997 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - The Ghost of Sifty-Sifty Sam - Drafts, 1991-1997 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - The Ghost of Sifty-Sifty Sam - Illustrations (b/w), 1991-1997 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - The Ghost of Sifty-Sifty Sam - Color page proofs, 1991-1997 (Map-case Drawer 6)
    - Rum-a-Tum-Tum - Research, 1991-1997 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Rum-a-Tum-Tum - Drafts, 1991-1997 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Rum-a-Tum-Tum - Galleys, 1991-1997 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Rum-a-Tum-Tum - Illustrations and posters, 1991-1997 (Map-case Drawer 6)
    - What Did I Do to Deserve a Sister Like You? - Note: working titles include "Nannie and Sharie," "Sharie and the Black and White Musical," and "Sharie Johnson: This Is Your Life!" - Typescript drafts, 1987-1995, undated (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - What Did I Do to Deserve a Sister Like You? - Note: working titles include "Nannie and Sharie," "Sharie and the Black and White Musical," and "Sharie Johnson: This Is Your Life!" - Typescripts and proofs returned from Atheneum, 1991-1996 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - What Did I Do to Deserve a Sister Like You? - Note: working titles include "Nannie and Sharie," "Sharie and the Black and White Musical," and "Sharie Johnson: Typescript, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - What Did I Do to Deserve a Sister Like You? - Note: working titles include "Nannie and Sharie," "Sharie and the Black and White Musical," and "Sharie Johnson: Illustration drafts (b/w) (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - 1998
    - Lucy's Library Book - Typescript drafts and correspondence, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Lucy's Library Book - Research, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Peanut Butter and Jam - typescript draft, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - The Picnic - typescript draft, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Poppa's Itchy Christmas - Drafts, 1992-1998 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Poppa's Itchy Christmas - Galleys (Oversize), 1992-1998 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - 1999
    - Beauty and the Bet - typescript draft, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - The Big Hit (Grade 1 textbook chapter)- correspondence and typescript drafts (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Daddy Saved the Day - Drafts and correspondence, 1997-1999 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Daddy Saved the Day - Illustrations and draft layouts, 1997-1999 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - 2000
    - Daisy and the Doll - Poster advertising author reading, 2000 (Map-case Drawer 6)
    - Daisy and the Doll - Poster featuring black and white photographs of Jessie Daisy Turner, 2000 (Map-case Drawer 6)
    - Seven Spools of Thread - Drafts, 1997-2000 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Seven Spools of Thread - Poster advertising author reading, 1997-2000 (Map-case Drawer 6)
  - undated
    - Annie's Christmas - typescript draft, circa 1987-1990 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Brekie the Brat - typescript draft, circa 1987-1990 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - The Chocolate Cake War - typescript draft, circa 1987-1990 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Daddy, What is War?- typescript draft, circa 1987-1990 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Greens - typescript draft, circa 1987-1990 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - I Wish I Had a Pair of Bubblegum Shoes - includes draft illustrations, circa 1987-1990 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Saturday Morning - typescript draft, circa 1987-1990 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - There's Nothing Worse Than an Elephant with a Cold - typescript draft, circa 1987-1990 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - What Can You Do with a Brown Paper Bag? - typescript draft, circa 1987-1990 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Books for Young Readers, 1987-1997
  Annotated drafts, typescripts, page proofs, galleys, correspondence, and notes represent the creation and development of Medearis' books for young readers. Materials have been arranged in chronological order, beginning with the earliest dates. Extensive annotated drafts and correspondence with editors and illustrators makes this series highly illustrative of Medearis' working process. Additional publisher and editor correspondence can be found in the Correspondence series, and Publicity correspondence in the Publicity series.
  - 1987
    - Black Life in the 1950s: The Photography of R.C. Hickman (unpublished) - Research and photographs, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Black Life in the 1950s: The Photography of R.C. Hickman (unpublished) - Synopsis and outline, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - 1990
    - Meet Addy - Research, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Meet Addy - Typescript (overview and chapter one), 1990 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Meet Addy - Correspondence, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - 1993
    - Come This Far to Freedom - Research, 1990-1993 (Box 8, Folder 11, Box 9, Folder 1-2)
    - Come This Far to Freedom - Proposals, 1990-1993 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Come This Far to Freedom - Typescript, undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Come This Far to Freedom - Typescript with correspondence, October 1990 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Come This Far to Freedom - "Original manuscript from Simon and Schuster" (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Come This Far to Freedom - Typescript with style sheet, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Come This Far to Freedom - Typescript, undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Come This Far to Freedom - Typescript, heavily annotated, with blue and white sticky notes, undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Come This Far to Freedom - Typescript fragments, undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Come This Far to Freedom - Typescript, annotated, with blue sticky notes, undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Come This Far to Freedom - Correspondence (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Come This Far to Freedom - Galley (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Come This Far to Freedom - Page proofs (oversize) (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Come This Far to Freedom - Mock-ups (oversize) (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Come This Far to Freedom - Cover art proofs (oversize) (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Come This Far to Freedom - Uncorrected advance proofs (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - 1994
    - Dare to Dream: The Story of Coretta Scott King - Research, 1992-1994 (Box 11, Folder 1-2)
    - Dare to Dream: The Story of Coretta Scott King - Early annotated typescripts, 1992-1994 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Dare to Dream: The Story of Coretta Scott King - Annotated typescript, 1992-1994 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Dare to Dream: The Story of Coretta Scott King - Dummy layouts, 1992-1994 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Dare to Dream: The Story of Coretta Scott King - Annotated typescript and galleys returned from publisher, 1992-1994 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Dare to Dream: The Story of Coretta Scott King - Galleys, 1992-1994 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Dare to Dream: The Story of Coretta Scott King - Three dust jackets, 1992-1994 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Dare to Dream: The Story of Coretta Scott King - Editorial correspondence, 1992-1994 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - The Seven Days of Kwanzaa - Original typescript, 1993-1994 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - The Seven Days of Kwanzaa - Annotated typescript, 1993-1994 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Mae Jemison biography proposal (1991-1994)- correspondence and research (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - 1995
    - "A Country Called Texas" (chapter in 4th grade Texas history textbook, by Angela and Michael Medearis) - Typescript drafts (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - "A Country Called Texas" (chapter in 4th grade Texas history textbook, by Angela and Michael Medearis) - Correspondence (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - "A Country Called Texas" (chapter in 4th grade Texas history textbook, by Angela and Michael Medearis) - Page layouts (oversize) (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - 1996
    - Treemonisha - Research (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Treemonisha - Drafts, 1990, 1992, undated (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Treemonisha - Illustration drafts (b/w) (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Treemonisha - First proofs (color) (oversize) (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Treemonisha - Partial galley (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Treemonisha - Editorial correspondence, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Treemonisha - Color photographs of undated production (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - 1997
    - Princess of the Press: The Story if Ida B. Wells-Barnett - Research (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Princess of the Press: The Story if Ida B. Wells-Barnett - Typescript (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Princess of the Press: The Story if Ida B. Wells-Barnett - Foul matter returned from publisher- photographs, copyedited typescript, galleys, page proofs, style sheet (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Princess of the Press: The Story if Ida B. Wells-Barnett - Dust jacket proof (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Princess of the Press: The Story if Ida B. Wells-Barnett - Editorial correspondence (Box 13, Folder 9)
- Cookbooks, 1994-1997, undated
  Annotated drafts, typescripts, and correspondence represent the creation and development of Medearis' cookbooks. Materials have been arranged in chronological order, beginning with the earliest dates.
  - 1994
    - The African-American Kitchen - Correspondence, 1993 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - The African-American Kitchen - Proposal, 1994 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - The African-American Kitchen - Partial typescript, 1993 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - The African-American Kitchen - Typescript (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - The African-American Kitchen - Page proofs (Box 14, Folder 5-6)
    - The African-American Kitchen - Publicity (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - The African-American Kitchen - Uncorrected advance proof (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - 1995
    - A Kwanzaa Celebration Cookbook - Rough proofs, 1995 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - 1997
    - Ideas for Entertaining from the African-American Kitchen - Early typescript (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Ideas for Entertaining from the African-American Kitchen - Typescript (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Ideas for Entertaining from the African-American Kitchen - Publicity (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Ideas for Entertaining from the African-American Kitchen - Correspondence, 1999 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Recipe Files, undated
    - Drinks (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Appetizers (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Side Dishes (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Vegetables (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Meat and main dishes (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Breads (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Preserves, etc. (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Caribbean recipes (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Desserts (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Children's recipes (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Photocopied sections of other cookbooks (Box 16, Folder 6)
- Articles, 1987-1995, undated
  This series includes drafts of essays and articles. Some include minimal editorial correspondence, and some include copy of item as published. Includes one piece by Michael Medearis.
  - Aftermath of a Disaster (Waverest fire), 1987 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - American Airlines stories (including story on Stephen Shapiro) (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Artists of Color in Texas, 1987 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Cartoonist Sam Hurt: From Esquire to Eyebeam, undated (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Clothes Encounter, undated (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Confessions of a Cat Hater, circa 1987 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Daddy's Girl (by Michael Medearis), undated (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Disc golf article proposal, 1987 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Don't Sweep My Feet: Old Wives Tales, An Oral Tradition, undated (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - The Gift That Lasts a Lifetime, undated (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - The Heart of a Gambler, undated (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - How to be a Great Boss!, undated (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Jacob Lawrence: No Resting on Laurels - Typescript draft, 1987 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Jacob Lawrence: No Resting on Laurels - Correspondence and research, 1987 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Juneteenth, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Junior Black Academy: Surviving Against the Odds (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - The Kwanzaa Celebration, 1995 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Life in the Sunbelt: Dallas, Texas, undated (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Lost Life of Sixth Street, 1987 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Overcrowding and Recidivism: A Response to Gae's Comment, by D. Farrington & C. Nuttal, Summary by Angela Medearis (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Pacifier safety article (proposals and research only, no draft of article) (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Perry Academy: A Not So Private School, circa 1988 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Pet Belts, undated (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Recycling - Hollywood Style, undated (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Saving a Little Bit of History, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Soundwaves, 1987 (Box 17, Folder 21)